number four asks a catalyst lowers the
blank for a reaction is it activation
energy change in entropy change in
enthalpy change in free energy if we are
looking at an energy diagram we have
reactants we have products this is going
to be the activation energy that's the
activation energy right there what a
catalyst does it is going to lower that
value it is going to lower the
activation energy so here's the new
activation energy there so this is going
to be a what we need to understand about
the catalyst is that it does not alter
any of these other parameters it does
not change the position of reactants or
products on the energy diagram for
example change in enthalpy or change in
free energy that is determined from
where the reactants sit to where the
products sit so if those don't change
their location none of those values can
change either all that we're changing is
the energy of the transition